Time runs out.
Tenet is a action, thriller, science fiction film directed by Christopher Nolan.
Armed with only one word - Tenet - and fighting for the survival of the entire world, the Protagonist journeys through a
twilight world of international espionage on a mission that will unfold in something beyond real time.
Protagonist, played by John David Washington.
Neil, played by Robert Pattinson.
Kat, played by Elizabeth Debicki.
Sator, played by Kenneth Branagh.
Priya, played by Dimple Kapadia.
Crosby, played by Michael Caine.
Tenet is a 2020 science fiction action thriller film written and directed by
Christopher Nolan, who also produced it with his wife Emma Thomas.
It stars John David Washington, Robert Pattinson, Elizabeth Debicki,
Dimple Kapadia, Michael Caine, and Kenneth Branagh.
The film follows a former CIA officer who is recruited into a secret organization, tasked with tracing the origin of objects
that are traveling backward through time and their connection to an attack from the future to the present.
Nolan took over five years to write the screenplay after deliberating
about Tenet's central ideas for more than a decade.
Pre-production began in late 2018, casting took place in March 2019, and
principal photography lasted six months in multiple countries.
After delays due to the COVID-19 pandemic, Tenet was released in the United Kingdom
on August 26, 2020, and in the United States on September 3, 2020.
It was Nolan's last film to be released by Warner Bros.
Tenet was the first Hollywood tent-pole to open in theaters during the pandemic and grossed $365 million worldwide on a
$205 million budget, making it the fifth-highest-grossing film of 2020 despite failing to break even.
The film divided critics but won Best Visual Effects at the 93rd
Academy Awards and received numerous other accolades.
The film explores themes of assassin, espionage, spy,
time travel, mumbai (bombay), india.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.